Tim Harrison



<u>tim@tjth.co (mailto:tim@tjth.co)</u>

Aim: To use my technical expertise and excellent communication skills to help a team achieve success.

Key Skills Cloud Management: I have over 6 years

experience working with AWS (EC2, S3, Cloudfront, EKS, IAM, EFS, Storage Gateway, Load Balancers, Autoscaling Groups, RDS, Cloudtrail, Cloudwatch, EKS, KMS). I also have experience working with GCP (Including GKE, Networking), Azure (limited) and other smaller Cloud Providers (Scaleway, Digital Ocean etc) as well as code hosting platforms such as Heroku.

Cloud Security: I have proven experience working with security services within AWS (AWS Config, Cloudtrail, Security Hub, Guardduty etc). I have also written design documents for AWS Client VPN, CIS Compliance etc.

DevOps: CI/CD (Gitlab / Github / Teamcity / Jenkins), Ansible (inc AWX), Building and deploying Pipelines, Docker (docker,docker-compose), Kubernetes (Helm, ISTIO, Velero Backups, Rancher, EKS, GKE) and IAC (Terraform, Cloudformation).

Communication Skills: Strong communication skills both written and verbal, both in team leadership and Customer facing account management to key stakeholders and budget owners (Including project and incident management with communication).

Network Management: Physical Networking, TCP/IP, VLAN, DHCP (Windows, linux DHCPD), DNS (Windows, Linux BIND), Cisco, Juniper, Wireless (Cisco, Ubiquiti), SNMP, Log management (ELK, Graylog), VPN (Openvpn, L2TP/IPsec), DNS and Domain Management, SSL Certificates (Inc Lets Encrypt), Two Factor Authentication (Duo Mobile, Google Authenticator), Network Security.

Server Management: Physical Hardware Management (Purchasing, Hardware + Software RAID), Virtualisation (Vmware, Hyper-V, KVM), Windows Server (2002-2019), Linux (Ubuntu, Redhat, CentOS), backups (Inc Acronis, VMWare, Windows Server Backup), Kubernetes, Docker, docker-compose, Monitoring (Nagios), Databases (SQL, MySQL, Mongodb, redis, redis-cluster), Log Management (rsyslog, Windows Events). Cloud hosted solutions (AWS, Azure, Digital Ocean).

Coding: Bash, Python, Javascript, Powershell, HTML, CSS, Code Versioning (Gitlab, Github, SVN).

Project Management: SOC and SIEM implementation, consultancy, Office 365 Migrations, P2V (Physical > Virtual Server Migrations), Brand Development (Inc Website, Corporate Branding, Marketing Campaigns) working to tight Deadlines with close Customer contact. Understanding of App Development processes (Agile) and different release methods (Canary, Blue / Green).

About Me

I am a self-motivated team player with experience in both heavily technical roles and client facing account management roles. I am a good communicator (both written and verbal) and have an ability to form close relationships with internal team and external shareholders.

I am flexible with working hours and travel and have held a full, clean UK driving license for >10 Years.

I am strong technically, with the ability to make strategic decisions under time and budget constraints and execute reliably.

Contact Details

- **2** +44 7872599064
- <u>tim@tjth.co</u>
 (mailto:tim@tjth.co)
- ☐ https://tjth.co
 (https://tjth.co)
- <u>in LinkedIn</u> (https://www.linkedin.com/in/tir harrison-47b11159/)
- **○** <u>Github</u> (<u>https://github.com/tjtharrison/</u>)

Hobbies:

While away from the Computer I spend my time working on DIY projects around the house and going on bike rides.

In the evenings I am working on a project combining my training with Python and React (Native) to build a mobile app with Python API

Achievements

DevOps - CI/CD Implementation: Built a CI/CD Pipeline from design through to implementation with requirements from team leaders - Combining Gitlab, Jenkins Multibranch Pipelines, Helm, Kubernetes, Slack, Jira (Transitions, RemoteLinks, Comments) and Private NPM Repository.

DevOps/Sysadmin - Documentation: Build a self-hosted Documentation platform based on Python. Ensuring processes are in place for documentation to be update for all system changes and systems to be self-documenting where possible (Eg using input from Nagios monitoring system for server config).

Consultancy - Office 365 Migration: Worked with a local charity to advise on the upgrade from their legacy POP based email solution. From this, I completed 0-Downtime Migration of 30 Mailboxes to Office 365 and migration from an on premise storage solution to Onedrive.

Set up Business and Tech Article Website: Set up my own Business creating Websites for clients, offering Consultancy and one-off projects. My website for articles based on my experience working with Linux servers and various applications consistently gets >500 Unique visitors per week.

Network and Server Management: Managed company servers, network, Cloud hosted servers (Including 24/7 Support). Replaced Legacy hardware with fully virtualised environment and resolved longstanding issues.

Bespoke Website with Database: Wrote a web application based in Python for Music Management startup, including Python Web UI (With account permissions), database backend (to Cloud hosted Database).

Employment History

Smart Pensions (April 2021 - Present) DevOps Engineer (Platform Security Team): I am currently working as part of a wider DevOps team of 20+ engineers, working on a range of technologies building, supporting and securing AWS via IAC (Terraform). I work in the Platform Security sub-team, working on implementing various AWS security infrastructure modules (AWS Config, Cloudtrail, Guardduty) including management of alerts via Datadog to our team chat platform.

I have lead a number of high priority security incidents, including communication to senior members of staff, detailed timelines and incident reporting (Post Mortem analysis) and am one of the primary security support engineer (Responding to alerts from Datadog and assessing before deciding on resolution path).

Xara LTD (Jan 2017 - April 2021) Senior Sysadmin / Devops Team Lead: Running a team managing local network (Servers, Desktops, Physical Network), 24/7 support for Production system, Project planning (Server Upgrades, Virtualisation, Cloud Migrations) and supporting internal staff, cluster of web servers. Working to delivery schedule to complete development tasks efficiently to cut expenditure while ensuring quality of service.

In this role I virtualised all in-house servers which were previously baremetal and migrated a large number of internal services to Docker / Kubernetes setup (Both in-house and AWS cloud hosted in EKS / EC2 / S3).

deployed on AWS hosted infrastructure (Infrastructure via Terraform).

I have lead the building of our internal DevOps team focusing on migrating services to Kubernetes (Including backups, monitoring, deployment and scaling) and assisting Developers to focus on coding by implementing CI/CD processes (Taking on existing Teamcity implementation and migration to Jenkins). A large number of internal Sysadmin functionality has been migrated to Automated Tasks, allowing for the Sysadmin Team to focus on Projects and Team Support.

iQuda (Jan 2011 - Jan 2017) Various Roles (Service Desk Management / Level 3 Technician): Rose quickly through the company, starting as a Web Developer before starting in Tech Support as a Level 1 Technician, moving through to Level 3 then onto Servicedesk Management and Project planning. This role included implementing and improving on processes and procedures, Customer account management and Reporting for Client contacts and internal management.

Education

AWS Solution Architect: I am currently working on my AWS Solutions Architect training and aim to complete the certification in the following Months.

Additional Courses: Udemy Courses in ITIL, Python, Kubernetes.

Parmiter's School: A Levels in Sociology, History, IT and English